Bruce MacDonald — Technical Writer

Cell	647 491 7106
\mathbf{Skype}	seenthattinker1
Skype No	864 810 1039
email	seen that tinker@gmail.com

Summary

I advocate open source for everything. I have worked on almost every system of content production available. I prefer the simple and direct approach of Markdown these days. My preferred operating system is Linux. I excel at standalone projects where the client has no existing methodology. In this space I can create excellent single source documentation for web, Docx, ODT, or PDF.

I believe the latest collaboration technology like GitHub makes working on documents a community activity, with the development teams commenting and editing and the technical writer crafting the final product with clean prose and information architecture.

Experience

Ataccama - October 2019 - Present - Senior Technical Writer

- Technical Communication Management Consultant
- Managing a conversion from Confluence to ReStructuredText. Web output with Sphinx and PDF templating for Latex and Docx. Twenty-two books for a combined page count of 3000. Off-site for first two months, then on-site for three months in Prague.

KPMG Global — June 2019 — Present - Senior UX Writer/Editor

- editing to best practices for KPMG Global's Cosmos application
- financial software for inside deals with KPMG and partners
- writing to a readable tone within a knowledge base of finencial services

Technisys — July 2019 — Senior Technical Writer

- edited a ${\it Confluence}$ Wiki and converted to Markdown for PDF production.
- financial software for custom workflows in banking

Hibar Systems — October 2018 — February 2019 — Senior Technical Writer

- manuals for precision pumps used in pharma and other medical and scientific manufacturing
- selected *Markdown* with pandoc as the toolset and applied a custom template to the docx output
- diagrams completed with LibreCad (2D).

Wilcox Bodies — July 2018 — January 2019 — Senior Technical Writer

- training material for new hires
- custom truck bodies for service providers like Ontario Hydro
- the processes transferred knowledge from stakeholders to new hires without
- selected reStructuredText as the toolset with Sphinx for web production
- support platform for new hires deployed on web with new hires given tablets to access

TD Bank August 2014 — October 2017 — Senior Technical Writer

- IBM Websphere, IHS, MQ, Dynatrace, SQL, DB2, Mainframe, Oracle, Cloud, CA-7, and Tivoli were the base technologies documented with occassional proprietary software for certain applications
- worked on the Application Response Management (ARM) team, dedicated to TD US
- developed a new documentation system based on DITA that simplified the information gathering process
- worked with vendors outside TD and internal engineers in development, support, and database management
- documented four to ten applications per month in a very fast paced environment

AMD September 2013 — March 2014 — Senior Technical Writer

- C Sharp API for graphics processing, leveraged from DirectX and OpenGL
- designed and created template with Libre Office and diagrammed with loose UML using DIA of Linux

Rad International November 2012 — January 2013 — Senior Technical Writer

- participated in a virtualization audit of all peripherals in an international bank, including digital checks, debit card readers, printers, etc.
- templated and wrote extensive documentation of business analysis, quality assurance experiments, operating system interferences, service pack interferences, load bearing capacities, network infrastructure, and database limitations
- worked closely with business analysts, project managers, company president, and bank business analysts and project members
- documented all meetings and to do requirements from the bank and then reported back with off-site testing results based on daily requirements updates
- ultimately audited every single process in the bank infrastructure related to virtualization in an effort to isolate and identify the cause of the hardware failures and inconsistencies in the deployment of new branches with machines cloud configured with a thin client and supported by the network/database driven virtualization
- wrote final report for the bank with all recommendations for change or reconfiguration in operating systems, service packs, and virtualization scripts worked with Microsoft Word and Visio

Sandvine June 2009 - October 2011 Senior Technical Writer

- wrote user guides, installation guides, policy language tutorials, command line interface reference books, and release notes
- improved the work process between engineering and documentation by securing access to quality assurance and development servers to directly engage the builds as the primary information conduit between documentation and engineering
- pioneered new ways to document the command line interface (CLI) by direct access to development servers, thus mitigating the need for engineers to write specifications
- improved the FrameMaker templates and the documentation numbering process for book parts and versions
- operated as the bridge between the Waterloo Ontario office and the Jerusalem office and provided oversight on all Jerusalem documentation products

- participated in the procurement of a content management system, a DITA front end (oXygen), and the maintenance of XSLT templates
- heavy knowledge base in all facets of networking: TCP/IP, Management Information Base (MIB), cable, DOCSIS, provisioning, and configuration hardware documentation as Sandvine had its own hardware division

Ministry of Government Services — January 2009 – May 2009 — Technical Writer

- produced several functional and technical specifications in cooperation with senior ministry engineers
- wrote in Microsoft Word and used Visio for diagrams
- product related to an internal messaging service designed on the Java Messaging Service (JMS)
- used Doxygen to map code visually through the dot graphics component
- documented the code to the Sun Microsystems standard
- wrote installation guide and user guide for the messaging system
- briefed management on all progress and ran weekly status meetings on the state of the project and the barriers to its completion
- wrote training material for government clients of the messaging service
- callback from earlier assignment with MGS

GTAA — February 2008 — November 2008 — Technical Writer

- wrote a new building code for the architecture department at the Toronto airport
- all builders, whether a confectionery like Starbucks in a terminal, or a new wing to the airport proper, were required to follow the building guide
- researched the Canadian Standards Association (CSA) building code as well as the American Standards Association (AMA) building code
- consulted with the senior architecture
- created a reference guide for all building materials allowable in the airport, from concrete to flooring tiles to wall material and studs
- worked on Microsoft Word
- restructured the guide to be more accessible as a reference guide

Previous Work

- Ministry of Government Services March 2006 December 2006 Technical Writer
- Rad International November 2005 March 2006 Technical Writer
- Vizible Software Sept 2004 November 2005 Technical Writer
- Syndesis July 2004 Sept 2004 Technical Writer
- Sodexho September 2001 September 2003 Technical Writer (Buffalo, New York)
- Ontario College of Teachers April 2001 September 2001 Technical Writer
- Siemens November 2000 April 2001 Technical Writer (**New Jersey**)
- General Electric August 2000 November 2000 Technical Writer
- Amway/Quixtar 1999-2000 Technical Writer (**Ann Arbor**, **Michigan**)
- Bank of Montreal 1998 Technical Writer

Education

Bachelor of Applied Arts, Journalism, Ryerson University, 1992

Personal

Avid reader and accomplished creative writer with two novels in ten years, good reviews in *Vancouver Province*, *Ottawa Citizen*, *Toronto Star*, *Globe and Mail*, *Calgary Herald*, *Quill and Quire*, and others. Literature is a great passion for me.

References

Professional references are available upon request.